# **Oliver Geoffrey Shepherd**

The Courtyard, The Green, Chiddingfold, Surrey, GU8 4TU

Phone: 07498 581894

Email: ogshepherd@gmail.com

# **Chief Operating Officer**

Experienced **executive**, having a successful track record of developing and growing high-performing teams and supporting systems in start-up and turnaround in both technology and property sectors, with a strong **focus on strategic planning and delivery**.

A resourceful and versatile entrepreneurial business leader. **9+ years senior management experience**. Credited with **combining Operational**, **Strategic and Financial expertise with strong interpersonal skills** in start-ups to PLCs. Significant experience of people, process management and systems implementation.

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

# Supporting CEOs and Key Stakeholders to Design and Deliver Strategy

- Supported CEO in developing, communicating and implementing the strategic plan for CSR Connect.
- Devised international B2B and B2C strategies for ITEMS for Health.
- Managed and co-ordinated best-in-class operational team across central functions including replacing and retaining outgoing General Manager at Star BMS.

# **Ensuring Successful Delivery of Operational Processes**

- Developed and oversaw best practise processes and systems across core functions at CSR Connect.
- Implemented operational platforms and processes to refocus a disconnected and regionally dispersed team at Star BMS.
- Developed efficient and effective delivery and on-boarding processes for ITEMS for Health, a SaaS software programme, to maximise user engagement.

## Implementing Digital Transformation Projects for Organisational Change

- Developed tailored ERP systems for CSR Connect and ITEMS for Health to incorporate CRM, Intranet, Marketing and Project Management.
- Managed the customisation, implementation and change management process for the successful takeup of a new CRM system for Australia's second largest body corporate manager.
- Led the development and implementation of an in-house CRM system for SEGRO Plc.

# **Client-Focussed Growth**

- Returned Star BMS to profitability within 12 months through driving new business and reducing costs.
- Managing business development at ITEMS for Health, including involvement in key client and partner meetings, leading to sales in three continents.
- Increased rent roll of mixed-use property portfolio from £29m pa to £33m pa for Derwent London Plc.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **CSR Connect (London)**

Jul 2019 - Present

An end-to-end B2B sustainability reporting SaaS system.

## **CO-FOUNDER & COO**

Supporting the CEO in strategic planning and execution, responsible for all operational activity.

- Full P&L, Budget and business planning responsibility, including marketing strategy.
- Employed new operations and sales teams.
- Engaged new remote development team.
- Responsible for a rebranding process.
- Devised and developed operational systems, processes and procedures to support growth and client management

## ITEMS for Health (Brisbane & London)

2013 - 2019

A talent management SaaS system provider with clients in Australia, Canada and the UK.

#### **CO-FOUNDER & COO**

Supporting the CEO in strategic planning and execution, responsible for all operational activity.

- Full P&L, Budget and business plan responsibility, including B2G, B2B and B2C marketing strategies.
- Devised and developed operational systems, processes and procedures to support growth and client management leading to 90%+ client retention.
- Managing key stakeholders, including investors, banks and partners to secure investment, finance and scale more rapidly.
- Recruiting and training sales, marketing and administrative staff both in-house and outsourced.

Star BMS (Brisbane) 2010 –2013

A property asset management company serving Queensland and New South Wales, Australia.

## **GENERAL MANAGER**

Acting with MD responsibilities, successfully performed a turnaround from loss-making to profitability.

- Developed strategy for recovery and growth, increasing revenue by 50% within 12 months and implementing major cost savings.
- Doubled the team and engaged agents across multiple sites to develop business.
- Developed systems and processes to address low engagement and business performance.
- Implemented tailored CRM system to improve efficiency and sales performance.
- Board presence at 93-strong parent company with \$20m per annum turnover.

# **Derwent London Plc (London)**

2007-2010

Derwent London is a FTSE100 company and the leading Central London Office REIT.

### **ASSET MANAGER**

Responsible for the asset management of a 1.4 million sq ft property portfolio.

- Managed internal and external sales teams to increased rent roll by £4m pa over three years.
- Key account management: Established and maintained tenant relations to maximise tenant retention and expansion. Completed a new lease at a rent of £960,000 pa.
- Managing cross-functional teams to ensure best service to clients;

SEGRO Plc (Slough) 2005 - 2007

A FTSE100 company and one of Europe's largest providers of business space.

## **LEASING SURVEYOR**

Led the letting of speculative developments on the Slough Trading Estate.

 Developed a new in-house CRM software system. The system acted as a management tool for the leasing process, a reporting system with various facets and applications

#### **Dreweatt Neate (Andover)**

2003 - 2005

A domestic and commercial property agency with offices across the South of England.

# **COMMERCIAL MANAGER**

Responsible for managing the Andover commercial office.

### Colliers CRE, (London)

2000 - 2003

Colliers CRE is a leading international property consultancy.

### **GRADUATE SURVEYOR**

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

Business Coaching Certificate, CTC (Distinction)	2016 - 2017
1-year Scalable & Saleable Entrepreneurship Programme, Sydney	2012 - 2013
Member of the Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors (MRICS), lapsed	2002
BSc (Hons) – Valuation and Estate Management, UWE, Bristol	1995 - 1999

#### **REFERENCES**